Mukesh Manral

Data Scientist - CloudyML

Profile

Tackling challenges in Data Science and Computer Vision. 1+ year of proven experience architecting applications using Deep Learning, Machine Learning and Python. Dedicated performer who demonstrates Curiosity, Intellectual agility, Statistical fluency, Research stamina, Scientific rigor and Skeptical nature to ensure quality and timely project completion.

Technical Skills

Python • Machine Learning • Deep Learning • Computer Vision • AWS •
AWS Sagemaker • Streamlit • Pandas • Numpy • scikit-learn • tensor-flow • keras • opency

Professional Experience

Data Scientist, CloudyML ⊘

June 2021 - present

Project-1: Customer Life Time Value Prediction

- Extracted and Preprocessed only required Records.
- Selected only required Features based on problem statement.
- Increase future sales by 2.6%
- Decreased churning customers rate by 4%

Machine Learning Engineer, TechSim+

January 2020 – December 2020

Client: One Financial Corporation

One Financial Corporation is a bank holding company specializing in credit cards, auto loans, banking and savings accounts.

Project-1: Loan Underwriting

- Preprocessed entire dataset and Selected most important 30 features.
- Boosted model efficiency by almost 5%.
- Validated model efficiency using matrix like classification Reports, confusion matrix, AUC Sscore.

Project-2: Customer Churn Prediction

- Preprocessed data and Performed Feature selection.
- Decreased churn rate by 2%
- Purposed different marking scheams as to retain churning customer

Certification

Master Data Science for Industry-(Ascend Pro), Link: ⊘

November 2020 – October 2021

- Attended 12 Months Training on Full Stack Data Science for Industry

- Institute : Analytics Vidhya

Got exposure to following areas of Data Science:

- Tools like Python, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikitlearn, Keras, Tableau, MongoDB, SQL, Spacy, Spark, AWS.
- Industry like Cusumer Market and Telecom, Financial Services, Life Science and Farma.

Machine Learning by Stanford University (Coursera),

May 2020 - July 2020

Link: ∂

Achievements

Machine Hack Data Hackon, Link: ∂

Global Ranking of 315

Kaggle, Link: 🔗

Pain Point: Like others I have to invested a ton of time and money in exploring Machine Learning and Deep Learning

AIM: To make easy to follow Machine Learning and Deep Learning framework in simple words Written easy to follow kernels on different Machine Learning Algorithms and Deep Learning

Github, Link: ∂

Sharing my knowledge with Data Science community

Education

Bachelor's in Computer Science Engineering, Uttarakhand Technical University June 2015 - July 2019